<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.aeroftp.AeroFTP</id>

  <name>AeroFTP</name>
  <summary>Modern Multi-Protocol File Client with AI, Encryption and Cloud Storage</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      AeroFTP is a cross-platform desktop client for FTP, FTPS, SFTP, WebDAV,
      S3-compatible storage, and cloud providers including Google Drive, Dropbox,
      OneDrive, MEGA, Box, pCloud, Azure Blob Storage, 4shared, Filen, Zoho WorkDrive,
      Internxt Drive, and kDrive. 18 protocols, 30+ presets, one app.
    </p>
    <p>Security and Encryption:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>AeroVault v2: Military-grade encrypted containers with AES-256-GCM-SIV, Argon2id, HMAC-SHA512, and optional ChaCha20 cascade</li>
      <li>Cryptomator format 8 vault support (scrypt + AES-SIV + AES-GCM)</li>
      <li>Universal Credential Vault with AES-256-GCM encryption and optional master password</li>
      <li>Archive encryption: ZIP and 7z with AES-256 password protection</li>
      <li>Memory zeroization for all passwords and keys (Rust secrecy + zeroize)</li>
    </ul>
    <p>AI Assistant:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>AeroAgent Pro: AI-powered assistant with 45 tools, shell command execution, RAG indexing, plugin system, streaming markdown, prompt templates, and cost budget tracking</li>
      <li>19 AI providers: OpenAI, Anthropic, Google Gemini, xAI Grok, OpenRouter, Ollama, Kimi, Qwen, DeepSeek, Mistral, Groq, Perplexity, Cohere, Together AI, AI21 Labs, Cerebras, SambaNova, Fireworks AI, Custom</li>
      <li>Vision/multimodal: Attach images for analysis with GPT-4o, Claude, Gemini</li>
      <li>Native function calling with streaming responses and cost tracking</li>
    </ul>
    <p>File Management:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Dual-pane file browser with list/grid views, thumbnails, and media player</li>
      <li>Archive browser for ZIP, 7z, TAR, and RAR with selective extraction</li>
      <li>Smart Sync with intelligent conflict resolution (3 modes)</li>
      <li>Batch Rename with 4 modes and live preview</li>
      <li>Monaco code editor (VS Code engine) with syntax highlighting</li>
      <li>Integrated terminal with SSH remote shell and 8 themes</li>
      <li>47 languages at 100% coverage — quality-audited translations with native script integrity</li>
      <li>AeroPlayer: Built-in media player with 14 visualizer modes, WebGL GPU shaders, 10-band EQ, and beat detection</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Built with Rust (Tauri 2) and React 18/TypeScript. Open source under GPL-3.0.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">AeroFTP.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>AeroFTP main window showing dual-pane file browser</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/axpnet/aeroftp/main/docs/screenshots/screenshot-1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Connection screen with saved servers</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/axpnet/aeroftp/main/docs/screenshots/screenshot-2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>AeroTools with code editor, terminal and AI assistant</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/axpnet/aeroftp/main/docs/screenshots/screenshot-3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/axpnet/aeroftp</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/axpnet/aeroftp/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/axpnet/aeroftp</url>
  <url type="donation">https://github.com/sponsors/axpnet</url>

  <developer id="com.aeroftp">
    <name>Ale (axpdev)</name>
  </developer>

  <provides>
    <binary>aeroftp</binary>
  </provides>

  <languages>
    <lang percentage="100">en</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">it</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">de</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">es</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">fr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">pt</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ru</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ja</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ko</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">zh</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hi</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">bn</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">tr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">pl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">nl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sv</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">da</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">fi</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">no</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">is</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">cs</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hu</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ro</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">uk</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">el</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">th</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">vi</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">id</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ms</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">tl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">km</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ka</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hy</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">bg</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">hr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sr</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sk</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">mk</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">et</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">lt</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">lv</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">cy</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">ca</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">gl</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">eu</lang>
    <lang percentage="100">sw</lang>
  </languages>

  <releases>
    <release version="2.6.10" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>CI Recovery and Release Realignment: Fixed a TypeScript parsing issue in ProtocolSelector that interrupted release builds, and re-aligned the release pipeline to publish downloadable artifacts correctly across supported platforms.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.9" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>Seafile Preset and Transfer Circuit Breaker: Added a pre-configured Seafile WebDAV preset with dedicated logo and full i18n coverage. Introduced a batch transfer circuit breaker with error classification, exponential backoff, reconnect handling, and retry-all-failed support for improved reliability during unstable connections.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.8" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>Selective Server Export: Export individual servers instead of all-or-nothing. The Export dialog now shows a checklist with Select All / Deselect All, color badges, protocol labels, and a live counter.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.7" date="2026-02-25">
      <description>
        <p>Update Restart, UX Polish and AeroCloud Multi-Protocol: Fixed long-standing restart failure on .deb, .rpm, and AppImage using setsid() detached relaunch. AeroCloud background sync now supports all 18 protocols via cloud provider factory. Dark theme modal consistency fix. Dynamic FTP TLS badge. Unified S3/WebDAV provider selector with info cards. Connection save race condition fix. SFTP symlink directory detection for NAS devices. 14 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.5" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
        <p>Dual-Engine Security Audit Remediation: Comprehensive security hardening based on dual-engine audit (8 Claude Opus 4.6 agents + GPT-5.3-Codex). 94 findings fixed across all severity levels — 7 Critical, 27 High, 54 Medium, 6 Low. Key fixes: constant-time HMAC comparison in AeroVault (subtle crate), bounded manifest reads (64MB cap), archive extraction path traversal guard for TAR/7z/RAR, 2FA enforcement in vault unlock, shell meta-character blocking, atomic writes for vault mutations and file saves, download size caps (500MB) across 13 providers, PTY session isolation, image resize bounds, SVG sanitization, credential redaction on profile import, unlock throttling with exponential backoff. Post-remediation grade: A-. 178 new i18n keys translated across all 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.4" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
        <p>Custom Server Icons and Favicon Detection: Custom icon picker for servers without dedicated provider logos — choose any image file, resized to 128x128 PNG. Automatic favicon detection for FTP/FTPS/SFTP servers using SIZE pre-check to avoid data channel corruption. Icon priority: custom icon, auto-detected favicon, provider logo, initial letter. Vault storage race condition fix ensuring icons persist across reconnections. Monaco source map dev warning silenced.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.3" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>AeroCloud Tab Switch and Menu Restoration: Critical fix for AeroCloud tab switching — switching from provider tabs (kDrive, Drime, etc.) back to AeroCloud now correctly disconnects the active provider before reconnecting. Session protocol routing expanded from hardcoded list to isNonFtpProvider() covering all 17 non-FTP protocols. Restored missing "Check for Updates" menu item in Help menu lost during VS Code-style titlebar migration.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.2" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>Amazon S3 Provider and Protocol Enablement: Dedicated Amazon S3 provider with 28 AWS region presets, official AWS logo, and simplified connection UI (no manual endpoint or path-style configuration). S3 bucket name trimming fix for IDNA validation errors. Azure Blob and Drime Cloud protocols re-enabled for production after successful testing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.1" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>VS Code-Style Titlebar and UX Polish: Unified VS Code-style titlebar with 4 custom dropdown menus (File, Edit, View, Help), theme-aware accent color hover, and migrated toolbar buttons. Native GTK menu bar eliminated. Cut/Copy/Paste in Edit menu with selection-aware disabled states. Consistent animate-scale-in animation on all 42 modal dialogs. Click-outside-to-close on AeroVault and Master Password dialogs. Default backgrounds updated (Waves for app, Isometric for lock screen). 147 provider security audit findings remediated across 8 cloud providers. ErrorBoundary and DebugPanel crash fixes. Settings button in titlebar. Simplified View menu labels in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.6.0" date="2026-02-22">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Ecosystem, Cloud Expansion and Provider Tier 3: Two new cloud storage protocols (Internxt Drive with E2E encryption, Infomaniak kDrive) bringing the total to 18. Four new AI providers (AI21 Labs, Cerebras, SambaNova, Fireworks AI) bringing the total to 19. Command Palette (Ctrl+Shift+P) with 25 commands across 5 categories. Plugin ecosystem with GitHub-based registry, SHA-256 integrity verification, Plugin Browser UI with install/update/remove, and event-driven plugin hooks. Context menu AI actions for instant file analysis. AI Status Widget in StatusBar with real-time state indicator. Drag and drop files to AeroAgent chat for analysis. AUR package (aeroftp-bin) for Arch Linux. 19 new i18n keys translated in all 47 languages. 8 dependency updates.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.2" date="2026-02-21">
      <description>
        <p>AeroImage — Built-in Image Editor: Lightweight image editor integrated into Universal Preview modal. Crop with Photoshop-style overlay and aspect ratio presets, resize with aspect lock, rotate and flip, brightness/contrast/hue adjustments with live CSS filter preview, blur/sharpen/grayscale/invert effects. Save As dialog with 6 output formats (PNG, JPEG, WebP, BMP, TIFF, GIF), JPEG quality slider, and replace-original option. Rust process_image pipeline for pixel-perfect output. Fix for auto-update installation on systems with localized Downloads folder names. 49 new i18n keys translated in all 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.1" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <p>Clippy Clean, Zoho Tab Icon and CI Fixes: Resolved 254 Clippy warnings across 42 Rust source files. MSRV updated from 1.77.2 to 1.80.0. Zoho WorkDrive session tab now displays official provider logo instead of generic WiFi icon. CI quality gates hardened with i18n validation scripts committed to repo. 3 missing protocol translation keys added to all 46 non-English locales. Dependabot configured with ignore rules for intentionally pinned dependencies.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.5.0" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <p>AeroFile Pro: Modularization, Tabs, Tags, Keyboard Navigation, Accessibility, macOS FinderSync, and event-driven volume detection. App.tsx modularized by extracting 730 lines into LocalFilePanel. Tabbed directory browsing (12 max, drag-to-reorder, persistence). Finder-style file tagging with SQLite (7 color labels, context menu, sidebar filtering). Arrow key navigation for file selection (Up/Down/Shift+Arrow for range). ARIA accessibility baseline (role=grid, aria-selected, role=toolbar, role=status). macOS FinderSync .appex extension for native Finder sync badges (6 states, Unix socket bridge, universal binary). Event-driven mount watcher (poll + inotify) replaces 5s polling. Network volume eject with fusermount fallback for SSHFS/NFS/CIFS. Mount point octal escaping fix for multi-byte UTF-8 paths. 23 new i18n keys across 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.4.0" date="2026-02-19">
      <description>
        <p>Provider Integration Audit and Zoho WorkDrive: 16th protocol with full OAuth2 and 8 regional endpoints. Comprehensive 12-auditor provider integration audit (4 phases, grade A-). Streaming upload refactor across 5 providers eliminates OOM on large files. All provider credentials wrapped in SecretString for memory zeroization. XML parsing migrated from regex to quick-xml 0.39. StorageProvider trait expanded to 18 methods with trash management, versioning, search, and share links. Cross-audit gap analysis: 18 findings fixed — HTTP retry with exponential backoff, provider error sanitization (95 occurrences), SFTP symlink-safe rmdir, AeroVault chunk AAD hardening, vault key zeroize on drop, cross-platform trash API, Windows volume enumeration via WinAPI. Resource management: all 17 issues resolved including local file scan 1M cap, Google Drive LRU cache, transfer pool validation. AeroSync Enterprise Intelligence: dry-run export (JSON/CSV), safety score pre-sync indicator, explainable sync decisions. SFTP TOFU visual dialog (SEC-P1-06): PuTTY-style host key verification with SHA-256 fingerprint display, MITM warning on key change, silent acceptance removed. Branded Polkit update dialog with AeroFTP icon and localized messages (10 languages). Auto-update restart fix for deb/rpm via detached shell relaunch.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.3.0" date="2026-02-19">
      <description>
        <p>Chat History SQLite Redesign: Complete rewrite of chat history persistence from JSON flat-file to SQLite WAL + FTS5 full-text search. 18 Tauri commands for CRUD, search, export/import, branches, stats, cleanup, and clear-all. Chat History Manager UI with retention policies (7/30/90/180/365 days or unlimited), full-text search with highlighted snippets, session browser, and statistics dashboard. In-memory fallback for graceful degradation. 55+ security audit findings resolved from 5 independent auditors. 24 new i18n keys translated across all 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.4" date="2026-02-18">
      <description>
        <p>Provider Marketplace, 2FA Vault, Remote Vault, CLI and Security Hardening: Searchable Provider Marketplace modal with 15 AI providers across 6 categories. 5 new providers (Mistral, Groq, Perplexity, Cohere, Together AI). TOTP two-factor authentication for vault master password with rate limiting. Remote Vault support for opening .aerovault files on connected servers. CLI foundation (aeroftp-cli binary with connect/ls/get/put/sync). CSP violation reporter. 13 security findings fixed from 5-auditor review.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.3" date="2026-02-17">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Welcome Screen and Shell Execute: Professional welcome screen with Lucide icons, 3x3 capability grid, API key setup detection, and clickable quick prompts. New shell_execute backend tool captures real stdout/stderr/exit code (replaces terminal_execute). i18n structural audit fixes 1188 leaked keys across 45 locales. Error message translation paths corrected. 29 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.2" date="2026-02-16">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent File Management Pro: 9 new tools (batch move, copy, trash, rename, disk usage, find duplicates, archive compress/decompress). Extreme Mode for fully autonomous 50-step AI execution (Cyber theme only). Relative path resolution fix for all 14 local tools. Connection context awareness distinguishes AeroCloud, server, and AeroFile modes. AeroSync modal now themed across all 4 themes via CSS custom properties. 13 new i18n keys in 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.1" date="2026-02-16">
      <description>
        <p>Splash screen menu bar flash fix (race condition in APP_READY_DONE timing). New Security Toolkit lock-and-key icon. New Cyber hacker theme icon. AeroCloud default sync interval set to 24h with inotify active.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.2.0" date="2026-02-15">
      <description>
        <p>AeroSync Phase 3A+ — Complete Frontend Integration and UX Maturity: Tab-based UX (Quick Sync + Advanced), 5 Speed Mode presets, Sync Scheduler, Filesystem Watcher, Multi-Path Editor, Sync Templates, Rollback Snapshots, parallel streams (1-8). Professional splash screen with 21-step simulated loading sequence. Advanced tab accordion for compact navigation. Password Forge extended to 24-word passphrases with BIP-39 disclaimer. Cyber shield icon. WebKitGTK scrollbar z-index fix. 31 security findings fixed across 6 independent auditors. Grade: A-. 47 languages at 100%.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.2" date="2026-02-15">
      <description>
        <p>AeroSync Phase 3A — Professional Sync Engine: 3 built-in sync profiles (Mirror, Two-way, Backup) with custom save/load. Conflict Resolution Center with per-file and batch strategies. Bandwidth control UI for upload/download speed limits. Journal auto-cleanup (30-day TTL). Backend progress throttle (150ms/2% delta) and parallel local+remote scan via tokio::join!. Plugin SHA-256 integrity verification. 39 new i18n keys across 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.1" date="2026-02-14">
      <description>
        <p>UX Polish, Icon Themes and Sync Reliability: 3-style icon theme system (Outline, Filled, Minimal) with per-theme defaults and auto-sync. Unified TransferProgressBar (7 bars into 1 reusable component with SpeedGraph). Aero Family branding complete. Fixed sync navigation false folder creation, AeroCloud CWD corruption on shared FTP connection, and session path restoration. Transfer toast theme/flicker fixes and splash screen removed for instant startup.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.1.0" date="2026-02-14">
      <description>
        <p>AeroSync Phase 2 — Operational Reliability: Transfer journal with checkpoint/resume for interrupted syncs, SHA-256 streaming checksum during file scan, structured error taxonomy (10 categories with retryability hints), post-transfer verification (4 policies: none/size/size+time/full), configurable retry with exponential backoff. Session tab context menu, insecure certificate confirmation modal, Filen 2FA compatibility fix, and 23 new i18n keys across 47 languages.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.11" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Complete i18n for Connection Intelligence: All 14 new connection logging and security badge keys translated across 45 languages with native quality. 360 placeholder corrections applied automatically.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.10" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Connection Intelligence, Security Badges and Windows Build Fix: DNS resolution with resolved IP in Activity Log, protocol step logging (TLS/SSH/HTTPS establishment, authentication, directory listing), secure connection badge (ShieldCheck with protocol abbreviation), 3-tier security model (insecure/warning/secure) in StatusBar, and suppaftp pinned to 8.0.1 to fix Windows build regression.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.9" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Smart Auto-Update with Platform-Native Installation: One-click Install and Restart for .deb, .rpm, .msi and .exe packages via platform-native tools (pkexec/msiexec). Smart asset availability detection retries hourly when CI artifacts are still building. Update toast UX redesigned with clear state progression. StatusBar badge re-triggers dismissed toast. 2 new i18n keys (openInstaller, skipForNow) translated in all 47 languages. Runtime version detection replaces compile-time macro.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.8" date="2026-02-13">
      <description>
        <p>Security Hardening, i18n Completion, Media Startup: Plugin shell injection eliminated (direct argv execution), TOFU host-key error branch hardened (fail-closed), localStorage OAuth fallback removed (vault-only credentials), terminal destructive command denylist, AeroCloud sync counters fixed with per-file activity details, security regression suite (5 automated checks with CI gate), settings migrated to vault-first storage, full locale key completion including Armenian, and Linux media first-play stabilized via buffered autoplay queue.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.7" date="2026-02-12">
      <description>
        <p>Translation Quality Audit: Comprehensive quality pass across all 47 languages. Eliminated 605 silent intruder keys (English values without markers), restored Armenian Unicode script from 63 Latin romanizations, applied 16 native Chinese corrections, standardized 173 placeholder formats, and translated 5 connection keys missing in 45 languages. Over 6,350 translations verified or corrected.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.6" date="2026-02-11">
      <description>
        <p>Theme System, Security Toolkit, Complete i18n: Four built-in themes (Light, Dark, Tokyo Night, Cyber) with CSS custom properties. Security Toolkit with Hash Forge (5 algorithms), CryptoLab (AES-256-GCM/ChaCha20 text encryption), and Password Forge (CSPRNG passwords + BIP39 passphrases). Terminal and Monaco editor auto-sync with app theme. 360 new i18n keys across 47 languages — zero untranslated strings. Monaco dev mode fix. About dialog updated.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.5" date="2026-02-10">
      <description>
        <p>System Startup, Tray Icon, Windows Explorer Badge and Provider Cleanup: Autostart on system boot with toggle in Settings (cross-platform: LaunchAgent, .desktop, Registry). Standard white monochrome tray icon. Windows Explorer native sync badges via Cloud Filter API and Named Pipe IPC server. OwnCloud provider removed after Kiteworks acquisition. Protocol Selector UX fixes. Security audit: 7 findings fixed (bounded reader, reject remote pipe clients, idle timeout, UNC path blocking, RwLock poison recovery).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.4" date="2026-02-10">
      <description>
        <p>Mission Green Badge, Folder Transfer UX and Transfer Reliability: Native overlay badges in Nautilus/Nemo file managers showing AeroCloud sync status (green checkmark for synced, blue arrows for syncing, red X for errors). Tray icon with overlay icons inside colored dots. Folder transfer cancel support, file-count progress display, path-aware logging. Transfer event system rewritten for zero event loss.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.3" date="2026-02-09">
      <description>
        <p>Production Rendering Fix: Critical fix for CSP nonce injection that silently broke all dynamic styles, Web Workers, WebGL, and IPC in production builds. Switched Monaco Editor to AMD loading for full WebKitGTK compatibility. Added DMABUF renderer workaround for Linux canvas artifacts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.2" date="2026-02-08">
      <description>
        <p>AeroFile Pro, Security Hardening and AI Provider Audit: Professional local file manager with Quick Look (Space), Trash Browser, Enhanced Properties (3-tab with permissions and 4-algorithm checksums), Disk Usage Treemap, and Duplicate Finder. Massive security audit resolving 70 findings across AeroAgent AI system (22 fixes, A-) and AeroFile file manager (48 fixes, A-) — including path traversal prevention, resource exhaustion limits, memory leak fixes, iframe sandbox hardening, and prompt injection defense.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.1" date="2026-02-08">
      <description>
        <p>Vault Unlock Fix and Provider Expansion: Fixed saved servers list appearing empty after master password entry. Added 3 Asian AI providers (Kimi, Qwen, DeepSeek) with official SVG logos. Added Custom provider preset for any OpenAI-compatible endpoint.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2026-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Pro: Professional AI assistant with 5-phase enhancement. Streaming markdown, code block actions, prompt templates, cost budget tracking, chat search. Anthropic prompt caching, OpenAI structured outputs, Ollama model templates and GPU monitoring. Gemini code execution and context caching. Context intelligence with project detection, smart context injection, and token budget optimization. DAG-based parallel tool execution, diff preview, intelligent retry, and composite macros.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.0" date="2026-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Super Powers, Unified Keystore &amp; AeroPlayer Engine — 17 new features spanning autonomous AI agent capabilities, RAG intelligence, extensibility, encrypted vault directories, enterprise-grade credential security, and a fully rewritten media player with WebGL GPU shaders.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>AeroPlayer: 14 visualizer modes (8 Canvas 2D + 6 WebGL GPU shaders), 10-band graphic EQ, beat detection, Cyber Mode</li>
          <li>WebGL shaders: Wave Glitch, VHS, Mandelbrot, Raymarch Tunnel, Metaball, Particles (ported from CyberPulse)</li>
          <li>AeroAgent: Multi-step autonomous tool calls, RAG workspace indexing, custom plugin system</li>
          <li>Ollama auto-detection, conversation export, system prompt editor, Monaco-Agent live sync</li>
          <li>Unified encrypted keystore with migration wizard and backup/restore</li>
          <li>AeroVault v2: Directory support with hierarchical navigation and recursive delete</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.9" date="2026-02-06">
      <description>
        <p>Dynamic Version Info, Credential Fix and Dependency Updates</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed critical credential save race condition for OAuth cloud providers</li>
          <li>Added vault write serialization (VAULT_WRITE_LOCK Mutex) to prevent concurrent write races</li>
          <li>Dynamic version info in About dialog (Rust, React, TypeScript, Tailwind detected at build time)</li>
          <li>Updated dependencies: Tauri 2.10.2, zip 7.4.0</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.8" date="2026-02-05">
      <description>
        <p>Security Hardening, Vision AI and Agent Intelligence</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Full security audit remediation: XSS prevention, CSP hardening, ZIP Slip fix, AI tool restrictions</li>
          <li>Vision/multimodal AI: attach images for analysis with GPT-4o, Claude, Gemini, Ollama</li>
          <li>Agent panel refresh: file panels auto-update after AI tool mutations</li>
          <li>Console.log gating behind debug-only logger utility</li>
          <li>Duplicate consolidation: formatBytes, getMimeType, UpdateInfo unified</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.0" date="2026-02-04">
      <description>
        <p>Smart Sync, AeroVault v2 Military-Grade Encryption</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Smart Sync with 3 intelligent conflict modes</li>
          <li>AeroVault v2: AES-256-GCM-SIV, Argon2id 128 MiB, HMAC-SHA512, optional ChaCha20 cascade</li>
          <li>Batch Rename with 4 modes and live preview</li>
          <li>Inline Rename with F2 or click</li>
          <li>Universal Credential Vault with optional master password</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.7.0" date="2026-02-01">
      <description>
        <p>Encryption Block, AeroFile Mode, AeroAgent Expansion</p>
        <ul>
          <li>AeroVault encrypted containers (.aerovault format)</li>
          <li>Archive browser for ZIP, 7z, TAR, RAR with selective extraction</li>
          <li>Cryptomator format 8 vault support</li>
          <li>AeroFile local-only file manager mode</li>
          <li>AeroAgent expanded to 24 tools with local file operations and batch transfers</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.6.0" date="2026-01-31">
      <description>
        <p>AeroAgent Pro: Native AI Function Calling and Streaming</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Native function calling for OpenAI, Anthropic, Gemini</li>
          <li>Streaming responses with real-time rendering for all 7 providers</li>
          <li>14 provider-agnostic tools via StorageProvider trait</li>
          <li>Chat history persistence with cost tracking per message</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.5.0" date="2026-01-29">
      <description>
        <p>Cloud Expansion: Box, pCloud, Azure Blob, Filen</p>
        <ul>
          <li>4 new cloud providers: Box, pCloud, Azure Blob Storage, Filen</li>
          <li>13 protocols total with 30 presets</li>
          <li>Native clipboard with cross-panel drag and drop</li>
          <li>Integrated terminal with SSH remote shell</li>
          <li>In-app auto-updater with download progress</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.8" date="2026-01-25">
      <description>
        <p>Global Multilingual Edition (51 Languages)</p>
        <ul>
          <li>51 languages including RTL support (Arabic, Hebrew, Persian, Urdu)</li>
          <li>Smart Overwrite Dialog with file comparison</li>
          <li>Properties Dialog with checksum calculation (MD5/SHA-256)</li>
          <li>MEGA.nz integration with end-to-end encryption</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-01-20">
      <description>
        <p>First stable release with FTP, FTPS, SFTP, WebDAV, S3, Google Drive, Dropbox, OneDrive support.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-info">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>FileTransfer</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>ftp</keyword>
    <keyword>sftp</keyword>
    <keyword>ftps</keyword>
    <keyword>webdav</keyword>
    <keyword>s3</keyword>
    <keyword>file transfer</keyword>
    <keyword>cloud storage</keyword>
    <keyword>encryption</keyword>
    <keyword>vault</keyword>
    <keyword>sync</keyword>
    <keyword>ai</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
  </requires>

  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
</component>
